Tony Schwartz Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
- Series 2. Business and Professional Materials, 1940–2005, 54 linear feet
  - Client projects: public service announcements (PSAs), circa 1940s–2002, undated
    - Creating a University Smoke-Free Environment correspondence, 1986-06-17–1986-11-05 (Box-folder 94/25)
      The group's acronym is CAUSE.
    - Crimestoppers scripts, report, and contracts, 1990-06-05–1990-10-15 (Box-folder 94/26)
      Intended for voice actors: Bob Landers, Alan Bleviss.
    - Cultural Institutions Group scripts, correspondence, and research, 1991-06-18–1992-03-04 (Box-folder 94/27)
    - City University of New York (CUNY) anti-smoking scripts, 1986-04-28 (Box-folder 94/28)
    - David's Island research and correspondence, 1989-10-29–1990-02-11 (Box-folder 94/29)
    - Department of Buildings, City of New York scripts and correspondence, 1986-04-01–1986-04-02 (Box-folder 94/30)
    - Department of Environmental Protection, City of New York scripts, correspondence, and research, 1985-08-14–1985-11-14 (Box-folder 94/31)
    - Department of Investigation scripts and research, 1983-03-23–1989-03-10 (Box-folder 94/32)
      Intended for voice actors: Alan Bleviss, Commissioner Kevin Frawley.
    - Doctors Ought to Care, 1977–1994
      The organization's acronym is DOC. Anti-smoking material.
      See also Martin Himmel Health Foundation scripts, KLBJ radio,
      - Scripts, 1988-12-12–1994-09-12 (Box-folder 95/1)
        Scripts and an American Federation of Television and Radio Artists HR reports.
        Intended for voice actors: David Goerlitz and Bob Landers.
        See also David Goerlitz materials, Michigan Billboards, American Cancer Society, and American Marketing Association.
      - Anti-smoking research, 1977-09-06–1987-07 (Box-folder 95/2)
      - Anti-smoking correspondence and research, 1981-04–1992-08 (Box-folder 95/3)
      - Anti-smoking scripts, correspondence, and research, 1985-11-05–1993-08-31 (Box-folder 95/4)
        Dr. Alan Blum. Includes interview transcripts.
      - Anti-smoking poster, circa 1977–circa 1987 (Box-folder 220/7)
        Black and white poster, 14x11 inches, mounted on a foam board.
      - Anti-smoking posters, circa mid 1970s, 1992 (Box-folder 229/8)
        Two anti-smoking posters, both color, from Doctors Ought to Care. The first, 22x14 inches, shows a young man, wearing a partially unbuttoned shirt, with a cigarette stuck in his nose; text: "I smoke for smell." The second, 24x13 inches, shows the Disney animated cartoon character, the Little Mermaid, on a tennis court attempting to bat away two sharks with a tennis racquet; text: "Doc presents Emphysema Slims ... You've coughed up long enough, baby! Kick the tobacco companies out of sports" (D. Minkler, 1992).
    - Dog Owners scripts, undated (Box-folder 95/5)
    - EMT's and Paramedics of Local 2507 scripts and reports, 1992-10-19–1996-01-12 (Box-folder 95/6)
      Intended for voice actor: Dan Ingram.
    - Energy Conservation Coalition scripts, 1988-03-31 (Box-folder 95/7)
    - Environmental Action's PAC scripts and research, 1986-10-28–1988-08-18 (Box-folder 95/8)
    - ERAmerica correspondence, undated (Box-folder 95/9)
    - Federal Trade Commission, 1972–1979
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research, 1972-07-06–1979-02-05 (Box-folder 95/10-12)
      - Reports, 1975-11–1978-03-20 (Box-folder 96/1)
      - Remarks and testimonies of Michael Pertschuk and Tony Schwartz, 1978-01-19–1978-04-07 (Box-folder 96/2)
        See also Pertschuk's correspondence, public service announcement files, and subject files.
    - Frank Field scripts, correspondence and research, 1987-10-01–1994-06-29 (Box-folder 96/3)
      Materials are concerned with fire safety.
    - First Alert, 1973–1995
      - Invoices, report, contract, 1993-06-30–1994-08-03 (Box-folder 96/4)
        Scripts, an American Federation of Television and Radio Artists HR report, and a contract.
      - Literature on Carbon Monoxide Poisoning materials, 1973–1993 (Box-folder 96/5)
        Large bound book of articles.
      - Scripts and research, 1993-01-13–1995-02-17 (Box-folder 96/6)
        See also SmokeFree Educational Services, Patrolmen's Benevolent Association, and City University of New York (CUNY) Health.
      - Research articles and statistics, 1994-02-07–1995-01-26 (Box-folder 96/7)
      - Research materials, 1993-04-27–1995-09-30, (1 folder) (Box 96-97, Box 96, Box 97)
        Radio transcripts from various stations.
    - Florence and John Schumann Foundation scripts, correspondence, and research relating to water conservation, 1991-04–1992-10-05 (Box-folder 97/2)
      Groups involved include: Hudson River Sloop, Clearwater Inc., Westchester Land Trust, Citizens Campaign for the Environment, Open Space Institute, Sterling Forest Preservation, Tip of the Mitt Watershed Council, Hudson River NERR, New Jersey Sierra Club, Appalachian Mountain Club, Passaic River Coalition, Ramapo River Committee, Tuxedo, Skylands Clean, New York New Jersey Trail Conference, and Long Island Soundkeeper Fund, Inc.
    - Food and Drug Administration materials, 1994-03-25–1996-08-28 (Box-folder 97/3)
    - Food and Hunger Hotline research, 1988-02-21–1993-09-20 (Box-folder 97/4)
      Includes an interview with homeless Korean veteran John Harrington.
    - Food and Water, Inc., 1975–1996
      Also known as MDI, Inc.
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research, 1988-11-30–1996-03-13 (Box-folder 97/5)
        Includes newspaper articles and American Federation of TV and Radio Artists HR reports.
        See also Landco Labs, Inc. receipts
      - Correspondence and research, 1975-02–1988-05-19 (Box-folder 97/6)
        MJI Broadcasting, Inc. correspondence.
    - Forum for Environmental Stewardship scripts, 1990-04-06–1990-04-07 (Box-folder 97/7)
    - Fund for New Priorities scripts, correspondence, and research, 1991-01-08–1991-01-11 (Box-folder 97/8)
      Funded by Military Families Support Network.
    - The Fund for Secure Energy materials, 1980-02-06–1983-11-09 (Box-folder 97/9)
      The fund's acronym is FUSE.
    - Garbage scripts, 1990-03-09 (Box-folder 97/10)
    - Gay Men's Health Crisis scripts, research, and correspondence, 1990-12-21–1992-02-14 (Box-folder 97/11)
      Intended for voice actors: Hattie Winston, Carol Emshoff, Alan Bleviss, Cookie Ruffino.
      Funded by Families Concerned about AIDS.
    - Rudolph Giuliani's drug campaign scripts, correspondence, and research, 1985-02-01–1986-12-08 (Box-folder 97/12)
      See also Patrolmen's Benevolent Association, Kaiser Medical Foundation, United Bank of Austin, and 1-800-COCAINE.
    - David Goerlitz articles, transcripts, and scripts, 1988-12-05–1990-04-14 (Box-folder 98/1)
      Anti-smoking materials relating to the former "Winston Man."
      See also American Cancer Society and Doctors Ought to Care, Goerlitz scripts.
    - Greater New York Hospital Association scripts, correspondence, and other material, 1984-11-07–1986-04-23 (Box-folder 98/2-3)
      Includes research materials and information about St. Vincent's Hospital.
    - Materials relating to the Greater Philadelphia Urban Affairs Coalition Program on Crime and Criminal Justice, 1991-04-19–1991-09-17 (Box-folder 98/4)
    - Greenmarket scripts, correspondence, and other materials, 1987-08-01–1998-08-27 (Box-folder 98/5)
      Includes research and billing items.
    - Materials relating to the Group Against Smoking Pollution, 1986–1989
      The group's acronym is GASP.
      See also People for a Smoke-Free Indoors.
      - Massachusetts correspondence and research, 1986-05-08–1987-09-20 (Box-folder 98/6)
      - New Jersey correspondence and research, 1986-10-14–1989-06-21 (Box-folder 98/7)
      - Virginia correspondence and research, 1986-04–1989-07 (Box-folder 98/8)
    - Guiding Eyes for the Blind scripts, correspondence, and research, 1992-04-26–1993-05-21 (Box-folder 98/9)
    - Handgun Control, Inc., 1987–1992
      See also Center to Prevent Handgun Violence.
      - Scripts and correspondence, 1989-02-09–1992-10-23 (Box-folder 98/10)
        Intended for voice actors: Bob Landers, Dan Ingram, Alan Bleviss.
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1990-04-09–1992-10-21 (Box-folder 99/1)
        Includes a color magazine ad.
      - Scripts and correspondence, 1991-05-17–1991-11-07 (Box-folder 99/2)
      - Research materials, 1987-04-02f–1988-08-29 (Box-folder 99/3)
      - Scripts and research materials, 1987-06-05–1988-03-14 (Box-folder 99/4)
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1988-11-16–1990-01-29 (Box-folder 99/5)
    - Handgun Violence Prevention Program report, 1986-08 (Box-folder 99/6)
    - Harvard School of Public Health research materials, scripts, and correspondence, 1985-01–1988-04 (Box-folder 99/7)
      Seat belt safety material.
    - Healthcare Crisis Taskforce scripts, 1990-03-23 (Box-folder 99/8)
      Intended for voice actor: Terry Beirn.
    - Holocaust Memorial Museum of Jewish Heritage scripts and correspondence, 1988-01-18–1988-02-03 (Box-folder 99/9)
    - Holyoke Energy Recovery Company scripts, research, and correspondence, 1985-07-19–1985-10-18 (Box-folder 100/1)
    - Home Port Information Task Force scripts, research, and correspondence, 1984-12-03–1985-10-25 (Box-folder 100/2)
    - Home Recording Rights Coalition correspondence, bill, and notes, 1990-03-22 (Box-folder 100/3)
      Concerns H.R. 4096.
    - Housing Control of New York scripts and research materials, 1983-06-22–1983-07-13 (Box-folder 100/4)
    - Hudson River Sloop Clearwater research materials, 1992-05-21–1992-06-21 (Box-folder 100/5)
    - The Human Society of the U.S. Wildlife Land Trust scripts, correspondence, and reports, 1995-02-16–1997-11-26 (Box-folder 100/6)
    - Indiana State Board of Health scripts and correspondence, 1989-11-14–1992-01-03 (Box-folder 100/7)
      Patrick Reynolds, anti-smoking material.
    - Insurance Information Institute scripts and correspondence, 1986-09-08–1990-11-16 (Box-folder 100/8)
    - International Ladies Garment Workers Union scripts and correspondence, 1981-05-02–1981-11-01 (Box-folder 100/9)
    - International Safeblood Foundation research, 1987-04-07–1998-08-20 (Box-folder 100/10)
    - Ariana Jaffee anti-smoking script, undated (Box-folder 100/11)
    - John Jay College of Criminal Justice, 1976–1995
      See also Concerned Students and Teachers of John Jay College, Schwartz's John Jay College teaching-related materials, and the John Jay College subject file.
      - Scripts and research regarding building for rent, 1988-07-22–1988-09-28 (Box-folder 100/12)
      - Scripts and correspondence regarding federal grants, 1976-11-01–1990-05-25 (Box-folder 100/13)
      - Enrollment-related scripts, correspondence, and research, 1977-05-04–1995-02-01 (Box-folder 100/14)
      - Interview materials, 1978-08–1979-04-26 (Box-folder 100/15)
        Includes drafts of the interview questions, as well as maps showing crime percentages in the John Jay College neighborhood.
        Interviews conducted by Ronald McVey.
      - Color photographs of John Jay College buildings and neighborhood, circa 1970s or 1980s (Box 202)
        Twenty-four 3 1/2x5 inch color photographs showing children playing with broken chunks of concrete outside a college building, building entrances and windows, and graffiti on brick walls.
        Photographic prints correspond to negatives in box 204/60-66.
      - Color negatives of John Jay College buildings and neighborhood, circa 1970s or 1980s (Box-folder 204/60-66)
        Seven 35 mm color negative strips showing children playing with broken chunks of concrete outside a college building, building entrances and windows, and graffiti on brick walls.
        Negatives correspond to photographic prints in box 202.
    - Joint Center for Political Studies correspondence, 1981-05-07 (Box-folder 101/1)
    - Kaiser Family Fund proposal from Tony Schwartz, 1985-05-20 (Box-folder 101/2)
    - Kids Against Public Smoking script, 1989-02-16–1989-02-22 (Box-folder 101/3)
      Intended for voice actor: Bob Landers. Anti-smoking.
      See also Smoking Control Advocacy Resource Center.
    - KKAR-AM correspondence, 1992-11-06 (Box-folder 101/4)
    - KLBJ-AM correspondence and interview transcript, 1983-03-11–1991-01-23 (Box-folder 101/5)
      Correspondence and transcript of an interview with Ted Smith on The Secrets of Effective Radio Advertising.
    - Lee Korobkin contract, 1992-02-14–1992-01-24 (Box-folder 101/6)
      Concerns organ donation.
    - KVET-Kase Broadcasting scripts and correspondence, 1993-11-18–1994-02-03 (Box-folder 101/7)
    - Lake Minnewaska scripts, correspondence, and research regarding property rights, 1986-01–1986-04-22 (Box-folder 101/8)
    - League of Women Voters research material, 1991-01–1991-04 (Box-folder 101/9)
    - League of Voluntary Hospital and Homes of New York scripts, correspondence, and research, 1984-07-19–1984-08-08 (Box-folder 101/10)
    - Lincoln Center scripts and research, 1986-07-14–1987-02-09 (Box-folder 101/11)
      Anti-smoking material in response to a Marlboro Country Music event.
      See also a photographic print of the Marlboro Country Music event banner in box 220/6.
    - Local 144 scripts and report, 1996-07-22–1996-07-23 (Box-folder 101/12)
    - Local 802 Musicians' Union scripts, 2000-06-22–2000-07-13 (Box-folder 101/13)
    - Scripts, correspondence, and other materials relating to Alison Gertz and the Love Heals campaign, 1989-03-11–1989-07-28 (Box-folder 101/14)
      Contains scripts, correspondence, interview transcripts, and research.
      Love Heals is a campaign to educate the public about AIDS; Alison (Ali) Gertz was its spokesperson.
    - Maine Nuclear Referendum Committee scripts, correspondence, and research, 1982-07-21–1982-09-09 (Box-folder 101/15)
    - Massachusetts Anti-Tobacco Project correspondence and research material, 1993-07-09–1993-08-11 (Box-folder 101/16)
    - Massachusetts Saving Lives Program scripts concerning designated drivers, 1988-08-26–1988-12-30 (Box-folder 101/17)
      Also known as Massachusetts Safe Driving Program.
    - Ken McFeeley obituaries, articles, and other material, 1986-05-20–1989-05-10 (Box-folder 101/18)
      Obituaries, articles, scripts, transcripts, and agreements concerning Ken McFeeley, a New York City policeman (and friend of Tony Schwartz) who died of smoking-related lung cancer in October 1986.
      See also the New York City Police Department materials relating to Ken McFeeley, the Martin Himmel Health Foundation, and the Patrolmen's Benevolent Association McFeeley file.
    - Media Insights scripts, 1994-01-17 (Box-folder 101/19)
    - Michigan Ballot Initiative scripts, correspondence, and research, 1989-12-08–1994-02-28 (Box-folder 101/20)
      Anti-smoking effort; includes research material for Alcoholics Anonymous.
    - Michigan Billboards, Doctors Ought to Care script, 1998-09-01 (Box-folder 101/21)
      See also Doctors Ought to Care.
    - Michigan Education Association script, undated (Box-folder 101/22)
    - Minnesota Moms for Healthy Babies correspondence, 1990-10-25–1990-10-26 (Box-folder 101/23)
    - Missing Person, Cathlene Fannin script, 1989-12-27 (Box-folder 101/24)
    - MQN Productions anti-smoking research and correspondence, 1993-06-24–1993-10-04 (Box-folder 102/1)
      Includes lists of cigarette radio campaigns.
    - NAACP Special Contribution Fund correspondence, photos, and scripts, 1967-01-04 (Box-folder 102/2)
      Includes 20 photos of impoverished families.
    - NARAL Foundation Education Project correspondence, research, and script relating to abortion rights education., 1980-01-19–1980-10-07 (Box-folder 102/3)
    - National AIDS Hotline scripts for the PTAAA (People Taking Action Against AIDS ) Ads Against AIDS campaign, 1992-06-18 (Box-folder 102/4)
    - National ALS Foundation scripts and research, 1979-04–1982-08-11 (Box-folder 102/5)
    - National Endowment for the Arts script, 1989-08-07 (Box-folder 102/6)
    - National Health Lung Study correspondence, research, and scripts, 1987-02-16–1988-04-11 (Box-folder 102/7)
      Contact: Ted Klein.
    - National Highway Traffic Safety Administration script, 2000-11-17–2000-12-11 (Box-folder 102/8)
      See also ABC radio network.
    - National Hospital Workers Union, 1199 scripts, 1981-07-02 (Box-folder 102/9)
    - National Law Enforcement Officers Memorial Fund, Inc. letter, 1990-03-13 (Box-folder 102/10)
    - National Victim Center correspondence, 1997-09-12–1997-09-25 (Box-folder 102/11)
    - Newington Children's Hospital scripts, correspondence, and other material, 1988–1990-04-27 (Box-folder 102/12)
      Scripts, correspondence, research, and contracts.
      Intended for voice actors: Bob Landers, Emilio Del Pozo, Toby Tarnow.
    - New Jersey Environmental Federation interview transcript, 1988-05-06 (Box-folder 102/13)
    - New Jersey Group Against Smoking Pollution scripts, 1991-02-21 (Box-folder 102/14)
    - New York City Board of Education health education reports, 1969–1983 (Box 102-103)
      - (1 folder) (Box 102, Box 103)
    - New York City Department of Health, 1985–2002
      - Scripts, 1985-06-17–1987-11-02 (Box-folder 103/2)
      - Clean Indoor Air Act material, 1988-03-17–2002-12-02 (Box-folder 103/3)
        Anti-smoking scripts, correspondence, and research.
      - Smoking-related signs, [1980s?] (Box-folder 225/12)
        Two copies (each) of two glossy smoking-related signs, each 10 1/2x10 1/2 inches. File also includes a bookmark-sized (2 1/2x6 1/2 inches) card with the text, "Please do not smoke in bed. The ashes on the sheet may be your own."
    - New York City Fire Department, 1982–1993
      See also NYMRAD awards.
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research, 1982-07-26–1993-03-09 (Box-folder 103/4)
      - Fire prevention radio spots, 1982-11-11–1983-08-10 (Box-folder 103/5-6)
        Letters from other fire stations around the U.S. and Canada requesting copies of public service radio spots made by Schwartz for the New York City Fire Department. Includes a flier advertising the spots.
    - New York City Police Department materials relating to Ken McFeeley, 1986-08-12–1990-10-18 (Box-folder 103/7)
      Anti-smoking materials, including scripts and correspondence.
      New York City policeman Ken McFeeley died of smoking-related lung cancer in October 1986.
      See also Ken McFeeley, the Martin Himmel Health Foundation, and the Patrolmen's Benevolent Association material on McFeeley.
    - New York City Police Foundation, Inc. letter, 1977-12-06 (Box-folder 103/8)
    - New York City Public Development Corporation materials, 1988-05-09–1988-06-08 (Box-folder 103/9)
    - New York City Water Department scripts, 1993-06-25 (Box-folder 103/10)
    - New York Commission Against Crime materials, 1982-06–1982-10-21 (Box-folder 103/11)
    - New York Fire Safety Foundation materials, 1986-07-28 (Box-folder 103/12)
    - New York Health Care Crisis Association scripts, correspondence, and research, 1985-05-17–1985-06-24 (Box-folder 104/1)
    - New York Medical Liability Reform Coalition, 1976–1985
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1976-01–1985-06-05 (Box-folder 104/2-3)
      - Research materials, 1984-03-02–1985-05-13 (Box-folder 104/4)
      - Scripts and research materials, 1983-04-14–1985-02-04 (Box-folder 104/5)
    - New York's Finest Foundation scripts and correspondence, 1983-10-06 (Box-folder 104/6)
    - New York State Martin Luther King, Jr, Commission scripts and correspondence, 1982-10-15–1985-12-16 (Box-folder 104/7)
    - New York Women Against Rape materials, 1984-09-07–1984-09-13 (Box-folder 104/8)
    - Non-Smokers' Rights Association, 1983–1989
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1987-05-21–1987-12-02 (Box-folder 104/9)
      - Correspondence and research materials, 1983-11–1989-01-13 (Box-folder 105/1)
      - Poster of two newspaper anti-smoking ads, 1986-09-17 (Box-folder 229/9)
        Black and white poster, 23x13 inches, showing two ads that appeared in Canadian newspapers on September 17, 1986. One side of the poster, with text in French, features an ad that appeared in the Montreal newspaper Le Devoir; the other, in English, displays a different ad that appeared the Montreal Gazette.
    - Letters concerning a National Public Radio interview about smoking, 1988-03-02–1988-03-23 (Box-folder 105/2)
      Letters in response to the NPR interview, including a large distribution letter from Philip Morris. Anti-smoking.
    - Office of Smoking and Health, Texas, contract correspondence, 1993-06-11 (Box-folder 105/3)
    - Ogilvy and Mather television script for gun control, 1990-10-24 (Box-folder 105/4)
      Advertising agency based in New York City.
    - Organ Donor Awareness scripts and reports, 1992-02-18–1992-04-17 (Box-folder 105/5)
      Scripts and American Federation of Television and Radio Artists HR reports. Includes materials relating to: New York Regional Transplant Program, New England Organ Bank, Organ Donor Group, Association of Organ Procurement Organizations, Association of Organ Transplant Organizations, United Network for Organ Sharing, and Coalition on Donation.
      Intended for voice actors: Alan Bleviss, Bob Landers.
    - Patrick Reynolds Foundation for a Smokefree America scripts, promotional items, and other material, 1988-11-04–1989-08-29 (Box-folder 105/6)
      Also includes transcripts, correspondence regarding an award for a Patrick Reynolds commercial from the International Film and Television Festival of New York, 1988, and eight portrait photos of Reynolds.
      See also the R.J. Reynolds family.
    - Patrolmen's Benevolent Association of the City of New York, 1981–1994
      The association's acronym is PBA.
      See also NYMRAD (New York Market Radio Association) awards, 1010 WINS radio scripts, an article about Tony Schwartz by Miguel Ongay in New York's Finest, and the PBA subject file.
      - New Concepts of Communication, 1984-03-08–1984-06 (Box-folder 105/7)
        Two drafts dated March 8 and June, 1984.
        See also Ken McFeeley, the New York City Police Dept. material on McFeeley, and the Martin Himmel Health Foundation.
      - Scripts and AFTRA reports, 1989-02-16–1994-07-19 (Box-folder 105/8)
      - Research materials, 1989-03-27–1993-08-01 (Box-folder 106/1)
        Some correspondence and notes.
      - Scripts and research materials, 1983-06-20–1986-06-20 (Box-folder 106/2)
        Includes New York's Finest magazines from 1987.
      - Scripts and research materials, 1980-08–1983-07-25 (Box-folder 106/3)
      - Scripts and research materials, 1984-11-29–1988-05-19 (Box-folder 106/4)
        Includes scripts and other materials relating to the Eleanor Bumpers controversy.
      - Photographs of police officers rescuing people, circa mid 1980s (Box-folder 220/8)
        Thirteen black and white photographic prints, 13x9 inches and smaller, relating to spots addressing the 1984 Eleanor Bumpers controversy.
      - Photographs of police officers in the line of duty, circa 1980s (Box-folder 225/13)
        Six black and white photographic prints, 14x11 inches and smaller, probably relating to spots addressing the 1984 Eleanor Bumpers controversy. Also includes a photocopy (17 x11 inches, in two pieces taped together) of an advertisement for the PBA that includes several of the photographs, and two copies (not identical) of a color poster or sign for the PBA (15x11 1/2 inches) that shows a police officer with blood on his shirt sprawled across a sidewalk.
      - Scripts, correspondence, and research materials, 1980-08-27–1983-06-29 (Box-folder 106/5)
        Includes a list of PBA tapes made by Schwartz and letters from listeners agreeing about a certain campaign.